DIANA M. KIRBY

UX DESIGNER

(615) 622-2280 **⑤** diana@weactualize.com **⑥** Nashville, TN **⑥**

<u>diana-kirby</u> 🐽

dianamkirby.org

SUMMARY

UX Designer with a background of 6+ years in psychology and human behavior and 4+ years in project management. Dedicated innovator with a hybrid-mind of creativity and analytics. Integrates design thinking and strategic problem solving to create and automate products and services that align with branding and business goals.

SKILLS

Wireframing & Prototypes
Personas
UX Research
Data Tracking
User Flow / Journey Map
Usability Testing
Design Systems
UI Design
Business Development
Strategic Planning
Marketing
Public Speaking & Training
Process Improvement

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Figma
Adobe XD
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Lightroom
Zeplin
Airtable (PMS)

EDUCATION

Certification

UX Design CareerFoundry, 2022

Master of Science

Clinical Mental Health Counseling Lipscomb University, 2016 Suma Cum Laude

Bachelor of Science

Psychology | Communications Harding University, 2014 Magna Cum Laude

FREELANCE & PROJECTS

Responsive Web Health Tracker: We Healthy I April 2021- April 2022

- Implemented mixed-methods research to discover user needs and product desirability for a responsive health tracker
- Established business report, branding, and strategic planning for viability
- Developed, iterated, and tested prototypes in Figma for developer-ready assets and design system in Zeplin

LinkedIn Feature, Semi-finalist Hackathon Winners | March 12-13, 2022

- Utilized existing market research to determine viability of a referral feature on LinkedIn
- Educated team on understanding the user via persona creation
- User flow, prototype assets, and CSS hand-off in Figma guided developers towards a feasible solution

Website Design: Presence Direction I June-August 2021

- Executed generative research to discover user needs for a practitioner's website offering spiritual direction services
- Defined scope as Project Lead
- Developed a website using Squarespace and delivered site to primary stakeholder for launch

Native Mobile App: Connect I March-April 2021

- Employed user interviews and user research to define needs and pain points for a language learning app
- Developed paper wires and prototype per project scope
- Iterated on designs and testing results to deliver a hi-fidelity prototype using Adobe XD

UX Writing: National Expansion of Mental Health Website | April 2021

- Conducted market research and defined project scope
- Wrote copy edits and recommended navigation menu restructure
- Provided marketing lead with wire sketches to deploy edits for rapid turnaround

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Design Freelance & Consulting

WE Actualize 2021- Present

Business Development & Operations

The Becoming: Counseling & Wellness | 2020- 2021

Project Manager

TN Dept. Of Mental Health & Substance Abuse Services | 2017-2020

Grants Management

Lipscomb University Counseling Center | 2015-2017